'Methil', C 35, Railway Colony, Sector 02, Vashi, Navi Mumbai 400703

# Objective: Seeking a leadership role in content in digital/print media

Professional summary: A successful stint in feature journalism; experience in handling a team of editors and writers towards developing and editing content in print and digital media

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Winner of the 'United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA)-Laadli Media Awards for Gender Sensitivity, 2007 in Print Media, for Best Feature (English), Southern Region, India (The story is now featured in 'Sense and Sensitivity' a book published under the auspices of Laadli, A Girl Child Campaign by Population First, and edited by Indian theatre personality Dolly Thakore)

### SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE

- Eleven-year experience in writing and editing, including stints in magazine, newspaper, and feature writing
- Four years collective experience in advertising, marketing, and events

My professional experience is across various fields, including advertising, events, marketing, content, and journalism. I not only gained relevant industry knowledge but also enhanced my latent skills. I believe I am capable of channelising any organisation toward achieving its professional goals.

#### **PRESENTLY**

### Freelance consultant and writer

- **Ideating, writing and editing in various genres** (February 2013 onwards)
  - Ghostwriting—my first such assignment, mythology-based, has been recently published
  - Working in the capacity of a content consultant with one of the leading luxury hotel groups based out of Mumbai, with presence across the country
  - Contributing features to tabloids and magazines including Femina, Mumbai Mirror, NCPA's OnStage, and Harmony Celebrating Age
  - Copy writing and designing e-mailers for corporates (The Walt Disney Company)
  - Copy for Annual School Calendar (Addhyayan School, Noida)
  - AV demo script for an internal-training module (Asian Paints)

#### PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

## Feature writing (Journalism)

Freelance feature writer / consultant—for various magazines and newspaper supplements/tabloids and websites (Feb 2013–to present)

Have worked on various kinds of human-interest stories and feature articles in publications like Femina verticals, Mumbai Mirror, Harmony Celebrating Age and OnStage (NCPA's magazine—the stories included those on legends like Pandit Hariprasad Chaurasia, Ustaad Zakir Hussain, Pandit Brij Narayan, Pankaj Udhas and Gulzar Sahab

Am also consulting content manager for a luxury hotel group, and have created content for a website called Katha Weddings (<a href="www.kathaweddings.com">www.kathaweddings.com</a>)

• Freelance feature writer—Vizag Plus: a supplement of Times of India, Vizag (May 2007–Jun 2008)

Focused on achieving a strong hold in the minds of the readers by taking to them human interest stories that revolved around current affairs, celebrity, and lifestyle

(I was the largest contributor to the tabloid, with an average of four bylines every week; one of those became front-page stories almost every week.)

• Feature writer/sub editor—Vizag Chronicle: tabloid of Deccan Chronicle (part of the Deccan Chronicle Holdings Pvt. Ltd.), Vizag (Aug 2006–Dec 2006)
Focused on human interest stories that centred around current affairs, celebrity, and lifestyle

(Most stories were front-page stories; some appeared on the broadsheet with impact follow-ups. One of my front-page tabloid stories won the '(UNFPA)-Laadli Media Awards for Gender Sensitivity, 2007' in print media, for Best Feature (English), Southern Region, India.)

## **Editing**

- Assitant Editor (Preproduction)—Femina, Worldwide Media, Mumbai (June 01, 2102 to February 2, 2013)
  - Handled sections in the main magazine, a task that includes coordinating with client servicing team, freelance writers and, of course, the heroes of the story
  - Worked on page making design software like InDesign and QuarkXpress; possess a high level of familiarity
  - Handled verticals like Femina Parenting, Femina Cook Book and Femina Bridal, while writing for them
  - Wrote stories for various sections, including those towards cover focus plus; human campaign stories—one of the primary properties of the magazine—and real life shockers, talking of shocking experiences some women across the country have endured and come through successfully
  - Ideated for cover stories, campaign stories and real life shocker sections in the magazine, besides the other sections on relationship, finances, interiors, reviews (books, restaurants, etc)
  - Ideated and wrote for stories on the Femina website (www.femina.in)
  - Contributed, wrote and edit/make advertorial pages, as required in the magazine
- Pre-Production Editorial Assistant—Femina, Worldwide Media, Mumbai (July 25, 2011 to May 31, 2012)

Involved in the production aspects of the magazine including editing, co-ordinating with designers and sometimes contributing to stories

• Associate Editor—Cactus Communications Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai: an ISO-9001 organization, committed to enhancing the quality of English across the world (March 09, 2009–July 20, 2011)

Edited, proofread, and finalised academic research papers, letters, reports, and legal proposals using guides like Oxford, CMS and APA, etc.

(I used to edit and finalise documents in both American and British English. My experiences here have enhanced not only my language and communication skills but also my general researching and referencing abilities.)

# Content/copywriting

• Freelance writer—Content for features on Zapakgirls.com: one of the biggest names among the country's Internet gaming industry (2008)

Feature content for online gaming site including articles and quizzes

• Freelance Content writer/editor—Population First: a Mumbai-based NGO (2008)

Developed communication material for "UNFPA-Laadli Creative Excellence Award 2007"

- Freelance content writer—Weblogix Pvt. Ltd., Vizag: an e-based company developing content for various organizations across the globe (Jun 2006—Mar 2009)

  Developed copy/content for internal communications as well as for their national and international corporate and individual clients
  - Freelance writer and consultant—Stanes Amalgamated Estates, Coimbatore/Nilgiris (Jun 2005—Apr 2006)

Created copy/content for brochures and website

• Senior copy writer and script writer—Anand Ads Pvt. Ltd., Vizag (Jun 1999—Mar 2001)

Responsible for internal/external communication across various media; developed script for a documentary film

• Copy writer—Trishna Advertising Pvt. Ltd., Kochi (Jun 1998–Mar 1999)

## Advertising and marketing

- Senior client servicing executive—Deadline Advertising Pvt. Ltd., Mumbai (Aug 2004–Apr 2005)
- Client servicing and marketing executive—Hyphen Communications Pvt. Ltd., Kochi (Sep 1995–Mar 1997)

Space and concept selling and marketing of films

## **Other literary pursuits**

 Have my own blog space at WordPress.com: http://interpreterofconversations.wordpress.com/

### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Microsoft Word, Power Point, high level comfort with softwares like InDesign and QuarkXpress

### **EDUCATION AND PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Post Graduate Diploma in Export Management—Cochin University of Science and Technology, Kerala, 1998

B. Sc Physics—Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, 1995

References will be provided on request.